# Kampelli Ravali (1) Featured

I am an enthusiastic Communication Systems Engineer who is actively looking to work in the fields of LTE, 5G, and other wireless technologies. I am skilled in C language, Python, Machine Learning, IBM Watson, and Matlab.



Current Designation: TECHNICAL ASSOCIATE Total Experience: 0 Year(s) 10 Month(s)

Current Company: CLAIRVOLEX Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: M.Tech [communication system

engineering] Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: C,Python,Machine Learning,IBM Watson,MATLAB,Simulink

Email - id Verified: Phone Number |

Last Active: 19-Nov-20 Last Modified: 6-Nov-20

### **Summary**

Result-oriented Professional skilled in C, Python, Machine Learning, IBM Watson, MATLAB, Simulink.

## Work Experience

**CLAIRVOLEX** as TECHNICAL ASSOCIATE

Feb 2019 to Till Date

Clairvolex Knowledge Processes Pvt. Ltd. as Technical Associate

Feb 2019 to Sep 2020

Technical Associate at Clairvolex. I prosecute patents related to 3G, LTE, and 5G. I prepare draft responses to the Office Actions issued by Examiners from U. S. Patent and Trademark Office and European Patent Office

Accenture as Associate Software Engineer -IT

May 2015 to Apr 2016

Hands on experience on PL/SQL

Part of ADM's Accenture CNC team from India

Provided authentication to the customers using ADM's website using QSoft tool.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from GNITS (G. Narayanamma institute of technology and sciences), Hyderabad in 2015

PG: M.Tech (communication system engineering) from Visvesvaraya National Institute of Technology (NIT), Nagpur in 2018

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
С		2015	3 Year(s) 2 Month(s)	
Python		2018	1 Year(s) 1 Month(s)	
MATLAB				
MACHINE LEARNING		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
IBM Watson		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

### Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Proficient			
Telugu	Proficient			
Marathi	Beginner			

### **Projects**

Project Title: Simultaneous Wireless Information and Power Transfer using Full Duplex NOMA Relaying

Client: VNIT Nagpur

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2017 - May 2018 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: The main aim is to harvest the energy simultaneously while transferring information. The main difference between half duplex and full duplex relay is self-interference. Decode and Forward (DF) technique is used to transfer information. Power is split for information decoding and energy harvesting. Two users are taken initially. The amount of power available for information decoding is multiplexed among two users on the transmission side multi-user signal separation on the receiver side is conducted based on successive interference cancellation (SIC). Energy harvesting is done when an outage occurs with the help of the amount power available for energy harvesting. This harvested energy is used for further information decoding. Since an outage event occurs when the source signal cannot be decoded at the destination or equivalently when the relay operates in energy harvesting mode, the main optimization target is to minimize the number of times that the relay does not transmit.

Project Title: Automatic Temperature Control in Vehicles.

Client: VNIT Nagpur

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2016 - Dec 2016

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: The main was to maintain the temperature inside the vehicle to the set point for whatever the temperature outside the vehicle. We have designed the Simulink model of temperature inside the vehicle. We have assumed the temperature variation to be sinusoidal in nature. Further we used fuzzy controller to bring the temperature to the set point. Inputs to the fuzzy controller were error in temperature and rate of change of error in temperature, Output was the control signal. Membership function we have chosen was triangular. Method of defuzzification was Centroid method. Mamdani model was used.

Project Title: Digital Watch Using GSM.

Client: G Narayanamma Institute Technology and Sciences, Hyderabad

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2014 - Apr 2015

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: As a digital clock displays the time digitally and often associated with electronic drives but the digital description refers only to the display not to the drive mechanism. Digital watches typically use 50 or 60 hertz a. c power or a 32768 hertz crystal oscillator to keep time. Our project includes GSM module which is an extension to a digital watch. The heart of this project consists of a microprocessor which can be interfaced with LCD for display, keypad for data entering and GSM module which communicates with the microcontroller using UART. It consists of RTC (real time clock) which is fed to microcontroller. This RTC is interfaced using I2C bus.

# **Affirmative Action**

Category: SC

Physically Challenged: No

# **Work Authorization**

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time